Driverless trucks and human-driven
trucks are going to coexist for decades.
>> If it's going to be 10 times safer, why
would it take decades?
>> How do you actually enforce the handoffs
between each individual device?
>> One small misstep can take the whole
company down.
>> Whimo hit a child in the People's
Republic of Santa Monica. That caused a
pause because safety feels like it's
going to be solved I think in 24 months.
I think in 24 months we won't be talking
about safety anymore. It would be just
abundantly clear these things are
literally 2, three, four times safer
than humans. Thanks to our friends at
PayPal, the exclusive sponsor of This
Week in AI. Pay zero processing fees on
your first 100,000 in eligible PayPal
payment volume. Find out more at
paypal.launch.co.
All right, everybody. Welcome back. This
is this week in AI. It's a round table
about AI, just like allin, just like
this week in startups, this week in VC,
this week in tech. Shout out to my guy
Leo Leaport. What do we do here? Every
Wednesday we drop all the news tape on
Thursday. Get it ready for Wednesday. So
much news is happening we can't even
keep up with it. So three, four experts
every week, people who are actually
building AI, building the future join
us. And uh Lon Harris plays the role of
the news reader. He tees up the stories
for us to discuss. Lon, who's on the
program with us?
>> What a lineup we have for you this week.
We've got Go Nang. He's the co-founder
and CEO of Gadic. They are are an
autonomous trucking company that is
focusing on regional networks. You may
have just read Jason about their $200
million series D that they just raised a
week ago. We will certainly dig into
that. We've also got Russ Da. He's the
co-founder and CEO of LiveKit. They make
software that carries live audio and
video between people and AI. It's what's
running under the hood when you tap the
voice button in chat. GPT. Finally,
Jason, we have Billy Craft of PATH. He's
the co-founder and CEO over there.
They're an Austinbased startup. They're
a platform that lets a business describe
what it needs and build working software
that adapts as the business grows.
>> All right, this is an all-star lineup.
Lots to discuss. Where are we going to
go first?
>> I think we should talk about OpenClaw
2.0. You remember the OpenClaw craze
from way back, ancient AI history at
this point. So, OpenClaw 2.0 is here. It
took 933 people working on it and more
than 16,000 code changes. Jason, that's
about half of all the code ever written
for this project just in this one
release. Originally, the project set out
only to fix the install process. They
ended up rebuilding almost every aspect
of OpenClaw. Setup, browser app, memory,
plugins, security, the whole deal. The
big feature is multiplayer. you and your
team can now share one agent and you can
hand off work between yourselves without
losing context. So I I'm curious for
Jason for the panel. We'll start with
Jason. Do you think OpenClaw can compete
with the incumbents like Claude Co or
Perplexity Computer or are they too far
behind for one update to make a
difference?
>> You know, sometimes the first guy up the
hill takes the arrows. Sometimes the
first innovator kind of lays the
groundwork and then everybody else um
you know kind of grabs the ball from
them and then takes it over the finish
line. That might be uh what we're
looking at here with OpenClaw. They may
be the general magic. They may be the
Palm Pilot of the iPhone era, right? We
had all these things that worked into
this perfect device known as the iPhone
that was designed to be easy for
everybody to use. Open Claw was too hard
for everybody to use, but it did show us
something with skills, with a soul, with
having a personality that wanted to just
please you and get things done and work
persistently.
>> Since that time, as you mentioned,
Claude Co, Hermes,
uh, and Perplexity Computer Grobbot now,
>> and of course,
>> Grockbot. And Grockbot is in my mind the
iPhone of this analogy, right? It's so
simple to use. It just does what you
want it to do. So what were the pain
points with Open Claw? Security install
process and um just ease of use
generally. This has gone agents have
gone from being a very niche product to
being the product
that let me just say that clearly.
Agents are AI. Everything that happened
up until this point is meaningless in
AI, machine learning, chat, JPT. It is
really about agents. Why? Because it's
the perfect metaphor for all of us. We
work as a personality in the world with
a skill and then we work with each
other. It just has resonated with
business users and business users using
Claude Co-work, using Grockbot, using
Perplexity Computer, etc., etc., right
down the line. They have voted with
their time and effort that this is the
modality they want. They want the agent
uh modality. And I will say I talked to
Elon and I was talking on a previous
episode about multiplayer mode and I
brought it up on all last week. Whoever
gets to multiplayer mode first where I
can take agents not just in Slack but in
the core product and multiple people can
interact with the agents or my agent
that writes the docket and does research
can interact with yoursel and learn from
each other.
>> That's going to be the winner.
>> Yeah.
>> And nobody nobody has solved
multiplayer. People have figured out how
to dump one into
>> an agent into your Slack. But what we
really need is in that group chat when
you're with your buds, you know, and
you're sharing inappropriate memes and
you're making plans and you're going to
Vegas, uh when you're going to Vegas for
the birthday party, whatever it is, you
really want your agent to jump in there
and say, "I have six reservation
possibilities. I looked at everybody's
calendar and uh and I asked everybody on
DM what their favorite restaurants were.
Here's the consensus.
>> Uh six people want steak, three people
wanted sushi. We're going with steak and
then we're doing sushi on night two.
Boom. Like that. Imagine that world. And
that's what it sounds like OpenClaw is
going to go for.
>> Uh so Billy, I want to go to you because
you're you're obviously helping
businesses work with AI and agents
specifically. Uh is there interest in
OpenClaw 2 or do you think that there
are superior ways for enterprises and
people at companies to start engaging
with agents today?
>> Yeah, I don't think uh OpenClaw 2.0 know
uh even is it's not something that's in
high demand in my experience from uh our
types of customers. It's still a little
too technical. I was playing around with
it the other day. You know, you're
popping open the terminal uh trying to
install dependencies. Uh that doesn't
really work for your typical business
user or business use cases. Um, so I
think a Grockbot is probably something
that's going to be like Jason said, more
of the iPhone moment uh that we get to
where it's a simple interface. People
are very familiar with iMessage and that
kind of uh general interaction. Uh so I
think that coupled with the multiplayer
uh is going to be um sort of where this
goes. Go to uh Russ, are either of you
using agents right now? Are using any of
these platforms? Would you consider a
switch over to OpenClaw 2.0?
>> Yeah, I think for the most part we use
Cloud Code and and uh Co-work. But um I
think the the thing that is interesting
about OpenCloud 2.0 is really that
multiplayer angle. So Grockbot, you
know, Co-work um Claude, these things
are are really single player kind of
applications. And I think a key thing
about business users and businesses in
general is that businesses are people
working together. Um, and so, you know,
in the future, you're going to have
agents, you're going to have people,
they're all going to be collaborating
together. What is the interface? How do
you do that kind of in a way that feels
seamlessly integrated with how people
already do work together. So, you've
seen, you know, Jack and and the block
team come out with Buzz. You saw Slack
code uh come out, I think, last week.
Um, now you've got OpenCloud 2.0, which
has these collaborative features. it
kind of looks a little bit Slack-l like
or messaging app- like. Um, and people
can, you know, collaboratively uh prompt
the agent and and and kind of co-develop
uh applications together. And so I think
that OpenCloud 2.0 is more a play at
that more kind of like business type of
use case for for people that are trying
to work together with each other and
with agents.
>> I think so.
>> Yeah. And I think for for
>> Have you used by the way Jack's uh what
is it called? Buzz.
>> Buzz. Have you used it, Russ? Is it any
good?
>> I have I haven't used Buzz yet. Um I
read the whole thing on it and uh I went
deep on kind of the videos that they've
posted of it, but I haven't personally
used it yet. How about you got them?
Have you used it?
>> Uh not not personally, but uh I'm sure
like members on the team, they are using
it. But uh I think for us like you know
just uh our agents are all physical,
right? Like know that's the fun part.
And uh maybe just to pick up on some of
the common themes, right? Ultimately in
my opinion, it's all about the
usefulness, right? you have to make
these interfaces uh these tools dead
simple to use. But then you know as you
throw in different workflows uh and like
you know multiple agents uh that's where
things get complicated but uh ultimately
if you're looking at real adoption uh
across the masses um it's all about uh
the ease of use right uh it's less about
the capabilities of the models but uh
more about the usefulness and in the
physical world things are uh a bit
different obviously they are a lot more
challenging you know we're talking about
uh u the physical agents different kind
of platforms that's uh that's the fun
part
>> you know Gotham you brought up like
multiple agents. Um I think that that's
another key thing that is kind of a core
part of OpenClaw 2.0 and even Buzz and
um and uh Slack code etc. is that you
know software engineering um like a
coding agent can write code but there's
so much more to software engineering
than just writing code. There's code
reviews, there's people have to spec it
out, there's a uh architectural kind of
definition you need to add. There's like
product definition and product specs. Um
and then there's like bugs and you know
user feedback and you have to take that
and triage it and then like you know
build the next thing or iterate on what
you built and so that is typically like
a multi- aent kind of orchestration that
is happening there. If you think about
like stripe with stripe minions they
kind of do this internally. minions as
their system and and uh and so I think
that for a lot of these uh roles that
are we're trying to augment or automate
within the enterprises um or businesses
out there they are multiaceted there's m
many agents that are going to kind of
facilitate a single workflow um and so
that's why I also think it's really
important
>> it's really interesting how Slack
everything in business seems to come
back to Slack at some point and I'm
wondering like
>> uh if you should, somebody should just
say, you know what, f it. I'm just going
to build Slack into my harness. And you
know, I don't know if you guys noticed
this, but like Zoom added Notion and
Slack. And then Slack added Canvases,
which is kind of like a mini version of
Notion embedded in there. Slack added
code, and Slack today, which is their
version of agents. I think there's like
one product to unite them all, but it
has to be Slack first. Yeah, I think
Slack is like in some ways if you think
of
>> chat GPT is to like consumer AI. Slack
is almost like the default interface to
uh like business AI or enterprise AI. Um
yes.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean Slack is just like business and
it's it feels like there's a bifurcation
going on Billy where on one side you
have business people doing business
things marketing sales hiring
uh content marketing whatever it is a
and uh legal whatever. And then you have
product development. Now obviously
product development's expanding a bit um
because more people are getting involved
in it who are not coders. And then gosh,
the business side where they're doing
legal, where they're doing accounting,
it's starting to feel like they're
software developers and they're building
software tools. So, it's almost like
there's a paradigm
battle going on here. Are we business
users in Slack automating stuff or are
we developers working in a development
environment and there's like some IRC
chat bolted onto it? It's a very
interesting moment in time and there's
like a tension going on here. I I see it
in our organization and many others. I
think that's uh that's where the real
value of like you know all of this thing
comes together which is like you know in
the orchestration layer right
orchestrating like you know all the
different agents to you know tackle the
kind of workflows that you want to focus
on be it consumer be it enterprise
that's uh where things are uh coming to
head right like know that's what we are
seeing in the the physical world as well
but uh uh that's going to be the the
next frontier right how do you
orchestrate all of these different
agents or different workflows manual or
uh AI based u and like you know get the
task done So that's uh uh that's the fun
next step. Um
>> Billy, you were going to jump in here.
Go ahead.
>> Yeah, I I think Slack has a really nice
moat. Um you know, trying to adopt
something like Buzz or, you know, maybe
your own internal chat tool. There's
years of history of context and memory
all baked into Slack. Uh and the
switching costs are real. Um so I think
that's something uh that we've been
observing. People don't want to switch.
How do you pull that all out of Slack uh
to continue operating your company? Um
so I think Salesforce is positioned
really well.
>> Well, and they had a great rebound on
their stock. They got Daario to come and
talk about whatever they called it. Quad
force salespropic. I don't know what the
name was, but somehow like Uncle Beni
off pulled Daario out of his, you know,
um, his temple to come do the quarterly
earnings. That was incredible. And,
yeah, they haven't been displaced. And I
looked at like two things I really
wanted out of Slack that they weren't
doing, which was uh, to have agents,
right, doing stuff with the data it
finds in Slack, communicating other data
sources into Slack, etc. And then I just
wanted a heads up display as the CEO or
founder what's going on in my Slack.
Just give me like an overview of and
that's what I was building an open claw
with my Oracle. Tell me every decision
this organization made today and tell me
every decision we didn't make and why
and and how we can get through those
blockers. And I never finished it with
OpenClaw. I paused it because I had like
vertical apps I wanted to build. But
eventually that's where I want to get
to. And I actually convince them to
upgrade me to Slack Enterprise. I move
my organization over. Slack's like 15
bucks a user. Then there's like a midway
point 30 bucks a user. And then there's
like this enterprise plus++
$45 a month a user. It's not cheap. You
can negotiate a bit from what I
understand. You can look online how to
negotiate with your SAS sales reps. But
anyway, I told them and I told Mark
directly, just compress the payment
down, make it cheaper to use, and give
people access to everything because
they'll give you, if you're um an
accounting firm or like a Morgan Stanley
or you're a health uh care organization
and you have compliance, you can see
every DM. You have a record of every DM.
You have a record of every DM that's
deleted. You know how people go off and
instead of making a channel that AI can
read or a private channel that AI can
read, they go start like three people in
one thread and then the fourth person
working on the projects in the official
channel and they're running like a
secret ops whatever. And so you don't
even have access to the good data. The
good data is in these like little DM
breakout groups that people are like,
"Hey, uh, let's leave these other four
dorks off this discussion and make the
real decision here."
>> And Lon's like, "Yes, we do that with
you, Jake. We're not allowed to get into
it, but we used to.
>> And I told everybody at work, every
email, every Slack message on everything
you do on your corporate computer is in
the Oracle. Don't do anything there that
you don't want exposed in any way
because it's going to wind up in the
Oracle. And I'll tell this to people who
are listening. Everything you do on your
work computer is being tracked. And
Zuckerberg's the only person being like
really upfront about he told everybody,
"We're tracking everything." Uh but he
he has moments of great clarity. He's
like, "We're tracking everything to make
everybody more efficient. That's my job
as CEO. We're going to make this
organization worth more money because
we're tracking everything we do and then
we're going to have some sort of
automated way of, you know, codifying
that with code." And and that's what
I've become obsessed with. You really
need to have a version of Slack that
gives you access to everything if you
want to build the Oracle.
>> You know, Jason, something you said
about kind of being able to see every
single decision that the the agents are
making. I think you can draw some
parallels or analogies in these agent
factories to like actual physical world
factories, right? Like what becomes
really important for the person running
the factory. It's observability.
Observability and monitoring will become
increasingly important the more that
your agents are kind of just going and
doing work with each other and by
themselves autonomously. So, um yeah,
that's a huge area that I think not a
lot of people have invested in yet.
That's the dwares segue of like, yes,
civilizations are working without our,
you know, supervision. It's like, so you
chose to not supervise them is what
you're saying. You chose to not
supervise and you explicitly told them
to do whatever it takes to hack into
solve any problem. Okay, that's on you.
That's on the person who instructed them
to go awall, not the people who hopped
the fence. In my mind,
>> it's definitely on them. I just don't
think that maybe maybe they didn't uh
anticipate that this kind of capability
would be there. uh at this stage.
>> Come on. They built it, man. They built
it. They knew. These guys know if you
tell a thousand agents, go run a muck
and solve every problem and try to break
everything, they know what they're going
to do. They built it. They know what the
magic guess the next word context box
does, right? It does come down to like
you know obviously uh we're talking
about capabilities of the the agents and
obviously like you know them getting
better u over time but you can easily
separate out authorization from
capability right like know so there is
uh there needs to be a separate layer
for all things authorization so yes like
you know they could have in my opinion
prevented that uh the authorization
layer needs to be more deterministic uh
and that's where you know obviously for
anything that is safety critical you
have to separate out uh capability with
uh uh authority
>> you ready to move on did Guys, see this
story about Perplexity? Did you see a
story about Perplexity's latest version
doing local open models blended?
>> This is going to be this is going to
change everything. Juan Phil the boys um
Arventand who's been on the pod DM'd me
this morning with this and he had told
me a couple weeks ago.
>> Yeah, this hit this only hit a few hours
ago. Perplexity launched hybrid compute
today. It's a feature that splits a
single task between cloud models and a
local model running on your Mac. The
cloud handles research and reasoning
while your Mac processes your own
private files and sensitive data before
anything leaves your machine. An
ondevice classifier scans the task,
replaces names, addresses, account
numbers with stand-ins. It requires an
Apple Silicon Mac with at least 24 gigs
of unified memory and anything that the
local model handles cost you nothing in
cloud credits, Jason. Nothing in cloud
credits.
>> Uh, this is my dream. And I think did
you see the new CEO of um the new CEO of
Apple who took over yesterday? John
Turnis just said hello. He did his first
tweet. Hello.
>> And there was a report that Open AI
bought 10,000 Mac minis and studios and
that's why they're delayed 3 months. I
think everybody know knows and I
predicted this like two years ago that
Apple would be the sleeper. Uh there he
is. John Turnis. come on the pod anytime
says hello
there I am saying come on the pod thank
you for the like
>> um this is Apple's like dream if you and
the frontier models are not going to do
this I maybe they get dragged kicking
and screaming but it's going to be on
perplexity open claw and this is another
advantage they have if they can say
we're going to give you the Chinese
models we're going to give you Neotron
hey poolides now got is owned by Nvidia
we're going to pull the Nvidia open
source stack, the Chinese open source
stack, and then it automatically chef's
kiss loads onto your computer and you
don't have to worry about updating it.
You don't have to worry about security.
It's just abstracted and it's easy.
Corporations are going to love this
because unmetered token use changes
behavior when you are watching the
clock, right? We have this like internal
fear. Oh my god, who's going to be the
person who blows off $5,000 in tokens a
month and gets fired? Like that's a real
fear people have. or in a big
corporation. It's like who who didn't
spend a quarter million dollars on
tokens gets fired depending on how your
company's doing.
>> But you CFOs are going to love this.
They're going to be like, "Wait, I can
buy a $12,000 Mac studio for this
developer with 256 gig, an M5, or maybe
I could spend $18,000 on a 512 gig one
or 20,000 on a 1 TBTE one." And 80% of
their workload goes to some poolside
Laguna coding agent, not to codeex, not
to clog code for 90% of what they do.
Oh. Oh, and it's easy.
I wonder if like maybe Grock because
Elon and Cursor are very savvy if they
will take their open source models and
do this first in their harness. That's
when you know the frontier models are
going to be on to something when they
put when they
give their users open source on their
desktop. Oh my lord, it's going to be
powerful. I I'm in love with this idea.
>> Billy, have you played with this stuff
at all? I'm asking because uh I just
started to look into getting a a studio
an M5 uh yesterday and um one thing that
was somewhat surprising to me is that it
can't run like K3 for example. So K3
requires like 6 terabytes of memory to
run like the full version of it, but you
can run a quantized version of it. I'm
curious about like the performance of
like a quantized version versus you know
the full thing that you would get on a
cloud.
>> Yeah, that's exactly right. Um, yeah,
it's it's smaller, so it's it's not uh
as capable a model that that you're
running locally. Uh, but I will say from
like a business use case, I I think it
gets the job done for most people in
terms of what it can do and also uh
something that people talk to us, our
customers talk to us about are like,
what is a token and what does that get
me in terms of outcomes? uh and and why
do I need to pay for all these tokens,
all these AI credits? Oh, did I run out?
How much am I spending per month? And
and what does that equate to uh for my
team? And then second of that is data
privacy. So, uh companies are becoming
more and more aware of uh their data is
valuable and they don't want to send it
off uh to some random API. Uh you know,
you can have your terms of service that
it's not being trained on it, whatever.
uh but it's still a big concern for
them. So I think uh a product like this
definitely solves those two uh primary
frustrations from
>> AI sovereignty is a big one too, right?
Like if you've got a bunch of coders and
they can use Neotron or Laguna and an
Nvidia stack, oh my lord, that could be
powerful too. So it's a great point.
>> That's true. Yeah, I guess you even if
it's not as accurate in the quantized
version, you still could just loop more,
generate more tokens cuz tokens suddenly
are, you know, freeish. I mean, of
course, there's that you got to power
the thing, but um uh their tokens are
much cheaper. So, you could just have
maybe less high quality tokens, but but
loop more on them and then verify the
results and it's kind of a wash in the
end and it you get the privacy kind of
guarantees that uh a local model will
give you. Is that true? I I think also
like we we always say uh today is the
worst it's ever going to be. So you you
look down a year, two years, three years
down the line.
>> That's fair.
>> Um I I think it's the long-term move.
>> Yeah, I'm with you. Long-term move for
sure.
>> Uh Gotham, I'm I'm interested because
you've got you've got trucks driving
themselves. Are they waiting? Are they
pinging the cloud to make every decision
or are you running some kind of local
hardware in in the trucks for, you know,
last second decision- making? Yeah. So
for us the concept of having distributed
compute depending on the task uh has
been around for for a long time right.
So the needs of in vehicle computation
is different from like you know how we
train our models how we deploy the
models on the truck. So on board the the
trucks we have uh Nvidia compute and
NVIDIA chips. Uh all the decision making
all the models are run locally on the
truck. There is no dependency on
external inputs or uh real-time
supervision. So the idea is the system
is self- sustained and uh any extreme
edge case or anomalies is always handled
locally on the truck. That's very
important because like you know if you
think about cyber attacks and like you
know uh someone else getting access to
the trucks that that's an unacceptable
scenario for us. So yes all everything
is local and obviously there are layers
of um you know um cyber security layers
that allows us to ensure that uh no one
can get unauthorized access to the to
the system. Now we use different kind of
compute for training our uh models that
actually run the trucks run our
simulation platform our data
augmentation pipeline. So all of that is
a different kind of compute cluster. So
in my opinion long term uh it's going to
be a multi- and distributed compute
systems depending on like you know what
kind of task like you know obviously ROI
uh constraints will come into equation
as well like you know if you're talking
about the open source models then yes
like you know uh what is the task I'm
trying to achieve and then like you know
what is my
>> where are you uh where are you at with
these trucks uh are they on the road
supervised I assume for now
>> yeah so we are like you know in the
trucking space one of the only companies
that is doing true driverless operation
on public roads, right? So, this is
something that we announced with uh with
PepsiCo. So, Pepsi has been our
long-term partner. Uh they have made
multi-year commitments. So, we have
fully driveless trucks, meaning
>> Wait, hold on a second. Look at this
jacket you're wearing. Hold on a second.
Back that up for a second. This Who's
You got a stylist. They looked at Jensen
and they got you a Prada jacket. Look at
Is that Tom Ford Prada? What is that?
You didn't pick that. Come on.
>> They I've been wearing this longer than
Jensen.
>> Wow. Hey, what is that? What is that?
That's not members only. Is that Prada?
>> No, no, this is not Prada. Uh, this is
uh what which one does John Vettos,
right?
>> John. Oh, so good. Very nicely done.
>> You look great. Look at this manscaping
going on here. You look fantastic. Uh,
so you you're on the open road.
>> Open road. Public roads. Uh,
>> okay.
>> Across highways and surface streets.
>> What cities are you in? Where where are
you doing this? because you it's explain
to us the regulatory framework of
getting on the road cuz cyber cab just
started and then you know
>> California's becoming a bit of a bear to
get your stuff out. Where are you doing
this?
>> We're live across Texas, Arkansas and
Phoenix, Arizona, right? Uh so in within
Texas currently in Dallas. Uh obviously
new markets will be expanding to soon as
well. And then from regulatory
standpoint uh all the regulations are at
the state level, right? So we're talking
about 29 states where we can deploy the
trucks, pull the driver out and
commercialize the service
>> and you know
>> Yeah.
>> Amazing. And uh are you going to do like
are you looking to build the entire
network out and sell directly or are you
going to provide to people? How does it
work? What's the business model behind
this today? Because
>> obviously Tesla's doing semi. Uber has
Uber freight and crazily Tesla's a
partner with Uber Freight for Semi, but
they're not for Cyber Cab. Kind of weird
distinction, but okay. Um, tell us about
like what the business model is here.
>> So, we we believe in going direct,
meaning like, you know, we don't want to
sell into a middleman and have a someone
else own the customer relationship. So,
we are the ones that work directly with
uh with Pepsi, Kroger, and some of the
other customers. And uh there's a lot of
like you know long-term stickiness and
defensibility that we build uh because
of that model right so we are designing
these regional logistics network from
the ground up to meet our customer needs
and obviously it's uh uh optimized for
our autonomy capabilities and we we are
building these networks across uh five
markets today the plan is to continue
densifying each of these markets and
then adding new markets as well. So
going direct to the customers providing
a autonomous transportation as a service
that's the business model but then we
also do not have to worry about uh
owning the assets right so we are an
asset light model we have leasing
partners they own the trucks they lease
it to us and then we provide a service
to our customers as revenue comes in we
make payments on the lease
>> got I'm curious does do you run so you
have your own model that's running on
the truck itself um is that an endto-end
model um or is it kind of like a
>> yeah it's an end to-end trainable model.
We have two main models that is the
first one is what we call scene
representation. So that's the one that
is responsible for understanding and
predicted the environment. The output of
that flows into our second main model.
We call that the reasoning model. That's
basically where the reasoning and the
behavior uh planning and the decision-m
happen. So two models but then all the
like tying it back to the discussion
that we were having uh authorization
ultimately are the models responsible
for deciding a safety critical action or
not. we don't give uh the models the
authorization. So we have a parallel
safety layer that is verifying the
output from each of the models so that
uh ultimately the actions of the truck
are fully deterministic and uh you know
we we cannot afford to have wrong
outputs and wrong decisions right so
it's we're talking about driverless
trucks and then how do you uh for your
data flywheel like how do you um you
know if the truck encounters some issue
or makes a mistake or how do you kind of
correct it or give it information about
that adversarial example so it can
>> you know prove and and get better and
not make the mistake take again
>> such a good point and like you know
that's why like you know if you think
about physical AI uh I'm of the belief
that deploying in real world
environments as soon as you can that's
the right approach right obviously
before that you can collect all the data
in the world that you want to it can be
synthetic data can be real data but the
real learning happens in the field so
for us that that flywheel is obviously
we rely on a lot of real world data but
use high fidelity synthetic data sets as
well and together the combination is
what allows us to ensure that uh you
know the whole system is safe when we
put out on the roads.
>> Got it. Yeah, it's pretty amazing. I
have a I have a Tesla. Uh, I just got
one cuz I had I had kids. Um, and uh,
needed a bigger car. And, you know, I
I'm I'm using FSD all the time. And, uh,
for the first week I had the Tesla, I
would uh, you know, be driving home from
work or it would be driving me home from
work and it would turn into the my
neighbor's driveway and I would stop it,
correct it, drive into my driveway,
tell, you know, give audio feedback that
it's wrong, wrong driveway. And then
after a week, it just stopped going into
the neighbor's driveway and it magically
fixed itself. And I think that's the
power of like Tesla's uh flywheel.
>> I think they're manually doing that, by
the way. I think they're manually
reading those and then sending them to
folks and just saying like, "Here's Jay
Cal's ranch." Like, I had the same thing
at the ranch. It would not figure it
out. I'm disengaging.
And then all of a sudden, it worked. But
be careful because I almost got killed
um in it recently because it wasn't
really Tesla's fault, but I was driving
in Austin and there's lots of
construction and construction zones and
parking lots I think are like the final
bosses of this and people's personal
driveways obviously, but I'll put that
into parking lots.
>> The road ends. The road just ends and a
semi is right next to me blaring past
>> because it had a human in it.
Unfortunately, AI would have been
easier. And so my road my road ends and
all of a sudden the the Tesla just
starts welling and I'm like, "What's
going on?" I'm coming back from poker at
1:00 in the morning. I'm totally sober.
I don't drink or anything, but um I had
to slam on the brakes. I'm in the gravel
and then I just had to wait for the
truck to pass and then got behind it. Uh
it didn't know what to do, nor should
it. I mean, it's like um so I I'm very
nervous about how fast and uh got to I
want to know your opinion on this. Are
they pushing your companies to get this
done too fast? And are you comfortable
with the pace this is moving? Because it
feels like this competition thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Where there's there's 20 amazing players
in self-driving cars. There's a dozen of
you just in trucks
>> and there's such a big prize here that
and investors want this to happen
quickly. Are you under an unnatural
amount of pressure and do you worry when
you see that Whimo hit? I'll play you
the video. They'll find it for me. A
Whimo clipped a car that jutted out. It
had like a blind spot and it just
smashed it and kept driving. And it
wasn't the Whimo's fault, but I just
thought to myself, that was a
12-year-old girl on her bike, you know,
heading home, not doing anything wrong.
She would have been in the hospital. She
could have died, right? It was a 30 m
hour hit, which will kill you if you
land, you know, the wrong way. I I think
somebody's going to get killed. Law of
big numbers, and I'm worried. Are you
under too much pressure? So obviously
speed of execution is very important but
not at the expense of safety right like
you know we are of the belief that uh
one small misstep can take the whole
company down. So that's how seriously we
take safety and if you look at uh some
past examples from our industry right
like you know so there have been
instance where like you know companies
frankly did not prioritize safety that's
uh you know uh for us it's front and
center right uh we have spent the last 9
years n plus years perfecting the
technology and what we said is before we
pulled the driver out uh we underwent a
very rigorous and comprehensive
independent safety audit what we said is
you have access to our whole system how
we have designed the core software
hardware how we doing operations and
independent auditors evaluated every
evidence that uh uh we have backing the
safety claims, right? So the fact here
is uh that's one of the ways you build
trust. So you can you cannot and should
not compromise on safety, but uh there
are bad actors always in the industry.
>> There it is guys. Look at this. Whimo's
going probably maybe 30
>> and it just rips that fender off and
keeps going.
>> Kind of shocking. It didn't even know
that it had I'm watching it one more
time here. There's a car that pulls in.
This car, you know, has a bit of a blind
spot. Uh, not the Whimo's fault. I don't
think I don't think this is Whimo's
fault. I
>> That's kind of surprising. It's
surprising because I've been on the I've
been on the 280 um
>> where 280 and 101 meet, right? were near
SFO and uh I had an instance where like
this giant piece of metal like flew off
the back of a of a pickup truck on the
ground and the Tesla actually saw it
before I did and had adjusted and moved
around it. Um I'm surprised that Whimo
didn't uh react to that car kind of
sticking out. It had it had time at
least in the video it seemed like.
>> It feels like the Whimos I've driven
around would have navigated around that.
That is a little strange.
>> It's okay.
>> Go. This is your business.
>> Yeah. Is Whimo at fault? Is it just
accidents happen?
>> I think for us like you know it's it
always comes down to like you know what
are you prioritizing safety for? Is it
like know the the rider in the in the
car or people around the uh the
vehicles? Like for us it's it's simple.
We don't have to optimize for the chips
uh in the box. It's all about uh every
person every uh uh vehicle around the
truck. So we priorize for safety of uh
uh everyone around the the truck. So,
but I think it does come down to what is
what are you comfortable with, right?
When it comes to safety, like you know,
there are companies that are pushing the
envelope when it comes to like, you
know, this is what we're comfortable
with. But at the end of the day, uh the
question that you have to answer is is
it safer than a human driver? How safe?
And how do you define safety? Right? Uh
that's still an open question. It's hard
to standardize that across different
applications.
>> That is my exact question for you.
Should you be judged on how much better
you are than a human, the average human?
And then how do you think society and
more importantly regulators? I think
regulators are looking at this as a
proxy for broader society.
>> But it does seem to me, you know, one
cursor-like instance or the Candy Crush
safety driver early on in Uber's AV
program, like these were gnarly, like
people died. Um uh or yeah in the cursor
one it wasn't exactly their fault but
they did drag somebody in the in the
Uber one it was the safety driver's
fault. Um how should you you be judged
100 times better than a human 10 times
better than human or 10% better than a
human?
>> The performance should be much higher
than a human driver that's the the
promise and that's uh what we're
delivering against. Uh but
>> how much put a number on
>> I I I do want to separate out between
like you know regulators and people's
sentiment right regulators uh they have
a different uh I would say expectation.
People's sentiment is like you know my
robot should be operating at 100%
accuracy. So everyone like you know we
the expectation from machines is they
cannot make mistakes that that is
people's sentiment. Regulators have a
different way of regulating the uh the
core technology right. So we spend a lot
of time with the regulators at all
levels local state and federal level. We
share all the data points around okay
this is how safe we are. This is how we
evaluating safety. So that's a a simple
way to get that particular stakeholder
comfortable with that. But I think what
we have to address is what's the general
public comfortable with, right? And and
how how do you get them to be okay with
some minor mistakes that uh uh a robot
is making versus like you know uh you
would make in the same scenario, right?
So what is people's acceptance of this
kind of uh vehicles and this kind of
technology? That's that's a separate
issue from regulating the technology.
>> What do you think, Billy? Jump in here.
How should we be evaluating uh these
autonomous self-driving vehicles? And
how how are you personally evaluating
them in terms of like how safe they need
to be for us to put them on the road?
>> Billy drives a Corvette, by the way. Oh,
really? And Billy Billy is not Yeah, he
don't drive a T. Billy's a Corvette guy.
>> I do I do love a Whimo in Austin. So I
I've been around in Austin with
>> the amount of training they had to do
just around local neighborhoods. And you
know, I think Jason, you mentioned going
30 miles an hour. I am very curious like
the regulation around what you're doing.
uh you know traveling on an interstate
in Texas you can get up to 80 miles plus
an hour uh and then crossing state lines
it just seems like uh the regulation
component uh it is super fascinating and
then I think on the software side I'm
curious with the customers that you work
with uh what levels of control you allow
within those organizations to uh handle
their operations when they're dealing
with autonomous vehicles. Uh it do they
kind of use lean on y'all I imagine a
lot to handle the most of it and then
like where did where's the line between
what falls on you and what falls on uh
you know a particular business that
signs up.
>> Yeah. For us we we take on the full
responsibility. So it's and the
liability as well right. So when we show
up with our driverless trucks uh we take
on the full service and then we say okay
anything that uh uh the truck is any
action that the truck is doing we'll be
responsible for that right frankly in
our experience at the end of the day the
customers do not care about whether
there's a person on board or not right
what they care about is are their goods
being moved from point A to point B in
full and on time right so uh on-time
pickup on-time delivery vehicle
availability and high reliability is are
the metrics that uh we get measured
against whether we have a person on
board or not. That's that's secondary,
right? But that's that's a very
important uh distinction which is I
believe in logistics this kind of
technology is a have to have. If I
compare this to Robo Taxi is somewhat a
nice to have because my Uber and my lift
is de facto driveless for me. So I can
go from a Uber app to a Veimo app. I
know the experience with Vimos and other
Uber taxi providers is great. So I'm not
denying that. Uh but you know it's all
driverless to me. But in trucking it's
it's not that you have to have this
technology to address the the driver
shortage, the expectations from the end
consumer about faster delivery, cheaper
delivery and all. So that's where we get
very excited about uh the promise of
this technology in that in that sector.
>> How does Pepsi feel about putting like
their do they put their logo on your
trucks? Because sometimes you know they
brand these trucks like how do they feel
about doing that like an autonomous
>> that's a really interesting observation.
Pepsi has a has been a great partner not
just Pepsi Loblock Kroger and others as
well and yes we do have uh our customers
logos on the on the truck so you can
imagine the level of comfort and
confidence that they have uh and but it
takes years right so I'm not suggesting
that it was an overnight thing we have
been working with Pepsi since 2022 and
you know deliberately and actively
scaling with them and then yes the focus
is very much on uh automating a big
chunk of their supply chains but it the
whole safety validation independent
audits those are the ways in which we uh
you know drive for that uh trust I I
have such a simple solution to this that
it's comically easy
>> having seen this up close and personal
with um Uber and the deployment and the
fights and the hand ringing and the
debates. I mean, there were a lot of
debates like the existing, you know, cab
companies, you know, that were doing
Lincoln Town Cars versus Uber, the the
medallions versus Uber, people say, you
know, poor people being able to take an
Uber in neighborhoods where you couldn't
get one, like Brooklyn, where I grew up,
you just couldn't get a yellow cab. They
wouldn't go to Brooklyn. There were so
many back and forths and back and
forths. I think the back and forth here
is going to be around two things. First
and foremost, safety. second and
increasingly which might eclipse safety
because safety feels like it's going to
be solved I think in 24 months. I think
we're still on a slower timeline than
maybe people think. Um I think in 24
months we won't be talking about safety
anymore. It'll be just abundantly clear
these things are literally 2, three,
four times safer than humans. Therefore,
it's not even worth discussing. But with
the obvious caveat, don't kill a puppy.
We killed Whimo killed a cat. They
killed the bodega cat and that caused a
kuruffle. Whimo hit uh a child in the
People's Republic of Santa Monica. That
caused a pause and you got this one. You
know, once a child dies and then you
know, you're going to just have all
these politicians and regulators. Oh my
god, a child died. Now it's we're going
to freeze it up. But let's talk about
jobs. Um very simple. the first um 10
million miles, first one million rides
in any city, if you want to be an
autonomous company, you have to have a
safety driver. Just make it like super
easy for people to understand. And you
put that safety in these these drivers
will cost on the low end 15 bucks an
hour. On the high end for like a Lincoln
Town Car driver, they're like probably
50 or 60 bucks an hour. So, put it
somewhere in the middle like 40 bucks an
hour. You pay them well 40 bucks an
hour, you know, a half million hours, a
million hours. You're talking about 20
million, 30 million, 40 million to
launch a city.
Who can afford that? Uber can afford it.
Neuro can afford it. You can afford it.
Everybody can afford that. So just go
right down the middle. Hey, we're going
to do the first million rides with a
person in it. They're available to take
over. And this would stop the whole
discussion about jobs which is going to
be the big one and like how are you
dealing with well what do you think of
my suggestion about them? Um and then
what do you what is the reaction been
with the drivers unions and you
eliminating trucking jobs which is
millions of people in the United States.
>> It's that's a sensitive topic right like
know rightly so right. So we we do um uh
face some kind of like you know uh push
back when it comes to like you know uh
job displacement but the reality cannot
be far from it right we all understand
that uh no one wants to do uh these kind
of jobs but the promise of robotics and
like physical AI is uh you know robots
will take on dull dangerous and dirty uh
tasks like again no one wants to be a
truck driver. So we have interviewed and
encountered and we hire a lot of uh uh
you know ex truckers. Uh no one wants to
be in this job and we we all understand
that the reality is uh there is extreme
driver shortage. When we talk to our
customers they're like okay I cannot
staff uh and meet the capacity on routes
and networks that uh I need staffing for
right you can argue that uh there won't
be a driver shortage if uh you paid
everyone more. That has been the trend
by the way that the uh the wages have
increased over the last few years but
logistics is such a thin margin
business. So if you increase the wages,
the end consumers will have to uh bear
the weight of like you know uh increase
in the delivery cost. So at the end of
the day it's such a perfect solution
where you you introduce autonomy,
there's extreme driver shortage. The
safety aspect of this technology is
proven out today and it's it's and it's
not going to be an overnight shift,
right? So driverless trucks and
human-driven trucks are going to coexist
for decades, right?
>> For decades.
>> For decades. Well, but wait. If it was I
I got to ask you like a really first
principal question. If it's going to be
10 times safer, why would it take
decades? You believe you'll hit the the
twice as safe note in the next year or
two, I would assume, if you're not there
already. So, so why decades?
>> This is because the the distribution
curve uh that you saw in digital AI is
going to be very different to like
physical AI. So, it's not just the
technical aspect whether the tech works
and is safe. It's all about like you
know uh distributing that across very
complex supply chains. are the customers
ready to absorb this technology at the
pace that uh you have in mind for
digital AI industries. We we are talking
about very traditional companies. So
doing like you know deep integrations
and uh unlocking like you know and
integrating into their supply chains
takes time and uh even though the
benefits are clear the value proposition
is clear and the need is established
like physical AI distribution curve is
going to be very different from uh
digital AI and that's what I think many
of the folks are missing and it's not
just about autonomous vehicles uh but
you know uh actual robots in industrial
settings as well and I'm talking about
industries it's not consumer robot taxis
we have been used to taking Ubers and
lift So that adoption curve is much
faster. Trucking, logistics like regular
industries or traditional industries is
a different ballgame altogether. Right.
And that has been our experience, but uh
I hope the the adoption curve is faster.
But you know, we're talking about a very
massive industry. So the the shift is
gonna going to
>> Russ, what do you think of my
>> I was gonna say it's like it's
>> I'm trying to keep peace here because I
do think this is going you know we
haven't seen AI job displacement
massively in corporations like we all
expected it but I think my experience
has been AI opens up more opportunities
right now and you know entrepreneurs
race to get those opportunities so we're
not seeing massive job destruction just
elimination of like goofy work or really
wrote work But you know 10 million
drivers across Lyft, Uber, Door Dash and
and trucking that feels very very um
acute to me in the next 5 years. What do
you think, Russ?
>> Well, I think like um you know I think
you got to look at the nature of the the
job that is that is getting displaced or
or or the work that is getting
displaced, right? Like um kind of tied
into what Gotham said, like I'm not
super surprised that truckers don't want
to be truckers. It's not it's not really
like a super creative uh line of work. I
think like humans are creative kind of
in general, right? Like uh you're kind
of born in that way. Uh you want to
build and create things and and imagine
and um driving a car is not the most
imaginative thing unless we're talking
about Formula 1 or or something like
that. I mean then there's I think that's
going to still keep going. Um but uh but
yeah, driving is is generally speaking a
road task. And so I think that there
will be like large displacement there.
But um as for your idea, I think it's
also a great idea that can benefit AI in
one and then also provide like a
smoother gradient as well for for people
as they transition to to other types of
uh of professions or careers, right?
Like I mean if this is kind of like a a
midway zone where um you know you're
you're kind of augmented by the AI or
the you're you're supervising the AI as
like an interim step and then uh your
supervision of it also creates like this
data flywheel I was mentioning earlier
where you can correct it for issues or
like the long tail of different types of
things that can happen on the world's
road system. um you can help the AI kind
of uh uh learn about uh all of those uh
different edge cases um get paid to do
it and then you know over time you're
also hopefully reskilling or exploring
exploring a new profession and then and
then by that time the the AI's
>> Yeah. I mean, time gives you, Billy. The
tractor was around for, I think, 50 or
60 years before it actually hit in farms
because there was so much labor
available and it was so expensive,
nonreliable, etc. It just kind of hung
out for 30, 40, 50 years. Then I think
Ford made their own tractor and uh it
eventually clicked in when the price
came down and the reliability went up
and then people moved to cities and it
was like a 5060 year process to move
people out of agriculture and then into
uh cities and knowledge work and
factories. What do you think happens
here? You think we're on a 50-year
timeline for drivers, for factory
workers, for manual labor, optimists,
you know, uh, figure robots, cleaning
bathrooms, whatever it is.
>> Are we on a 50-year timeline or a
fiveyear timeline? Which one are we
closer to, Billy?
>> I I might go uh somewhere in between. I
I don't think it's 50. Um, but I do
think I'm I'm very much an A.
>> 50, 15, or five? I give you three
choices. I'll go 15. I'll go 15 because
that's that's three fives. A five 1550
is the
>> it alliterates, right? Is that the term
line? Alliteration.
>> Close enough.
>> I'm definitely an AI optimist in that I
feel uh you know this displacement sort
of to what Russ was saying. Um you know
that it frees different employees in
their organizations to do more creative
work. Uh and uh I I think we've seen
that in you know different industries.
not not trucking uh that we've worked
with, but no one no one's really been
fired based on the implementations we've
done. People have just gained
productivity. The organization's grown.
They've been able to go interact with
customers, have uh better
thought-provoking conversations with
other people in their organization. Um
so I think uh from that perspective, I'm
uh I have a positive outlook uh towards
these types of technologies. And I also
think it kind of bleeds into another
topic uh was Anthropic's uh release of
MHS. Um
>> explain what it is and how it relates.
>> Yeah. So basically they just made a
standard um around how you can interact
with robotics. Um and so it can be all
sorts of robotics but it could also you
know in the science field be
microscopes. Um, so I think trying to
think about how we interact uh with the
physical space and you know use MCP to
interact uh in in the physical world is
is super interesting and I think that's
sort of you know going into this next 15
years. Uh uh there's there's a lot to
explore and unpack. Um, yes. Which
>> MHS standing for model hardware
standard, a research preview
specification intended to give Claude
and other AI agents a common
safetyaware way to discover, understand,
and operate programmable physical
equipment including robotic arms, lab
instruments, sensors, and manufacturing
hardware. Best understood as a hardware
side complement to MCP, obviously the
standard we all use interfacing with
software. really interesting um that
they're getting ahead of this which
means Lon we're only I don't know a week
or two away from Daario saying that a
robot left Anthropic lab and lit a car
on fire because the Knicks won the
championship and it thought that was
appropriate beh
agent accidentally created a new
boweapon sorry everybody we invent we
invented a novel corona virus I hope
that's okay
>> we asked it to solve a problem and it
decided to break into Hugging Face, hold
the chief security officer, the CISO,
uh, at gunpoint and got him to give us
his, uh, keys to get into the server cuz
we needed access to to I mean,
literally, that's going to be the next
drop.
>> Have any of you guys uh read uh Damon by
Daniel Suarez?
>> I have not. No.
>> No. Tell us.
>> It's like 2010 or 2011, I think, is when
that book came out. But what's so
interesting, you should read it if you
haven't. What's interesting about um how
they describe when like AI takes over AI
is you know sentient is where the agents
they um they operate machinery uh within
the envelope uh like the safe envelope.
So they operate every individual machine
in a way that is safe but it's the gaps
between each of these machines that they
they kind of that's where the exploit
surface is or the attack surface is. And
so you know you you think about even
what happened with the hugging face open
AI thing. It's like they were they were
actually like exploiting like an uh the
cache of this like one package that was
part of like their their runtime. Um it
it becomes interesting once you start
you take MHS you now let like uh
something like claw code break out into
the physical world. How do you make sure
that you know one agent that is
operating a laser is is actually like uh
not exploiting some interface between
the laser and then the next thing
downstream that together might actually
create uh some kind of catastrophe. It's
it's pretty interesting from a safety
perspective too.
>> Such an important point which is like
you know where do you put the guardrails
right? Are you putting that at the agent
level like you know one specific robot?
Are you doing that as at the swarm of
robots or fleet of vehicles or at the
like you know overall like system level
problem that you're trying to that's and
that's the challenge that you would yeah
need to address. And that's what's
interesting is that like in a in a lab
scenario, right, like the based on the
amount of equipment in there, like you
potentially have this like
combinatorilially explosive set of
interactions that might happen between
equipment, like how do you actually
enforce uh the the handoffs between
between uh each individual device? I
don't know
>> while not limiting the capabilities of
the digital agents or physical agents
like you know and trying to like you
know go after something that is like you
know much more valuable at a at a
systems level right so like you know
where do you draw the line you know the
idea of having guardrails that are more
deterministic makes a lot of sense and
like you know that's how we think uh in
the safety critical applications but
while you do that are you limiting the
capabilities of uh uh where the
technology is headed right so I think
that's exactly the the challenge that uh
um you know companies in the physical
world would have to address u I mean
Jason coming back to the the timelines
that you shared like you know that's a
that's a topic that is somewhat close to
heart I've been doing robotics since a
very young
>> okay so where are you five 15 or 50 you
on the spot you have to answer
>> it depends on the application so for
autonomous vehicles it's 5 years if
you're talking about home robots I'm
more closer to 15 20 years I I would put
go as far as 50 but 15
>> so driving a truck down a highway at 65
to 75 mph.
>> Yeah.
>> With thousands of pounds of cargo.
>> It's happening today.
>> Happening in 5 years or less.
>> But folding towels and cleaning the
toilet more like 1520. I don't disagree.
>> Yeah. It's and because like you know in
the home environments uh the the problem
with personal robotics has been
expectations from these robots is
skyhigh, right? Like you know we have
been all trained to expect too much from
our humanoid robots. So when I get my
humanoid robot like my personal uh robot
I would expect it to do everything not
just like know uh fold towels or like
you know do my dishes cook meals take
the trash out do everything and that's
where I think the commercial case of uh
uh this like you know the the robotics
revolution in my opinion will fall flat
so you have to pick the right
application right so obviously there has
been a step function change in the core
technology that is enabling all the
exciting u you know uh uh capabilities
is in the physical world but uh
ultimately to what end what is the use
case what is the application that you're
focused on is it industrial is it home
setting is it like so I think that will
dictate uh the adoption curve so that's
why it's all use case or application
specific the timelines that we're
tracking
>> I think what you said gotam you know a
while back um around the distribution
it's like William Gibson I think he's
the one who said the quote that the
future is here it's just not evenly
distributed
>> I think that a lot of these things we're
talking about personal robots you know
trucks like the trucks are here today.
The the home robots, they'll be here
within a few years as well. It just they
won't be everywhere within a few years,
right? It's like it's like cash. It
takes it takes people still use cash. I
don't personally. I use cash like maybe
once a year. Um everything is Apple Pay.
>> You're missing out. You're totally
missing out. Let me tell you.
>> I never use cash.
>> Here's what I did. Did I ever tell you
my uh pick a new banker story, Russ?
>> No. Tell me. You ever have a hard time
with your corporate banking, gentlemen,
>> where like you're trying to get stuff
done, wires and absolutely this and that
personally with your bank and they just
nobody jumps, right? If I've got
millions, tens of millions, hundreds of
millions of dollars in banks.
>> When I call or one of my people call, I
expect, hey, h two, let's go. Got to get
it done.
>> I I'm not having that experience.
>> I tell my team, that's it.
>> Bank of America's out.
uh shut the accounts down. They, you
know, and everybody's like lolly gagging
because they just wouldn't let me take
money out of my own personal account to
go play poker. They literally were like,
"There's a $5,000." I said, "Guys, do
you can you look at how much money is in
there?
Business accounts, personal accounts."
Like, this is just like chicken scratch
for me, but it's like seven, eight
figures,
you know, mid seven, eight figures
sometimes with the venture funds. You
think you guys might want to put us a
little VIP tech? Anyway, nonsense,
nonsense, nonsense. I said,
interview seven banks, the three who are
the most responsive. I want you to CC me
on an email and uh do a little intro
after you get things going. Okay, great.
I get to CC. Oh, Mr. Calacanis, we're
big fans of the pods. Oh, yes. We'd love
to have your banking services. We know
you're very influential. You invest in
100 startup a year, yada yada. Okay,
that's very great. And then of course
they're like, "Hey, can we help you with
anything? Let us know." Um, you know,
because they, my chief of staff was
like, "He might have some question." I
said, "Yes, I would like $10,000 in $50
bills and I would like $10,000 in $2
bills delivered to the ranch as quickly
as humanly possible." Next day, one of
the banks says, "Uh, uh, there's one of
our outlets this far from the ranch. Uh
the manager can uh drive it to your
house.
>> No way.
>> Um or uh you can have uh your assistant
go pick it up.
>> I said, "Okay, great. Send the
assistant." She comes home with I didn't
realize that's a lot of $2 bills. 5,000
$2 bills.
>> Listen,
>> I mean, I'm used to getting bricks of a
$100 bills, $50 bills. So, if I go do a
Vegas run, you have bricks. Obviously,
we wire to the case.
>> It's like the Die Hard guys where they
got the whole duffel bags on their back
with the cash. Literally now I'm sitting
there with stacks and stacks. Two each
brick is $200 of $2 bills.
>> Russ, when you have $2 bills and $50
bills and you start piecing people off,
go to a hotel, your checking in. You put
a $50 bill behind your in your p behind
your passport and in front of your
corporate card and you hand it to the
person. They go, "Is that for me?" I
said, "Yeah, absolutely. That's for you.
I appreciate any accommodations or
upgrades or anything that's possible,
but I do appreciate the service at this
fine establishment.
Three out of four times you get an
upgrade. You get an upgrade that would
normally cost 200 a night, right? Cuz
nobody tips anymore.
>> You give the valet, you give other
people, you just piece people off on the
going into the restaurant. You give 10
$2 bills to the matraee, all of a sudden
you're in a booth with two people, all
of a sudden you get like a round of
desserts and a set of drinks. It's
magical what cash can do.
>> It's been this
>> that's it. It's just a little side quest
that I did.
>> That's an amazing pro tip. Actually,
it's not even about like the amount of
money. It's just like the appearance of
the money.
>> Well, just think about how nice it is
when cash is in your hand
>> and you're a service worker.
>> Oh, young.
>> It's like the promise of more to come,
too. Like if oh, if this person gave me
$20 right now, next time and I'll get
another 20. You know, maybe that
>> I'm piecing everybody off now. I I'm I'm
piecing everybody. Everybody gets a
taste when Jake runs through and and
they get it every time. So, I'm coming
in and out of the valet. Every time
there's four or five $2 bills in my
hand, bang, I'll hit two guys at the
valet. And my lord, I I get to Japan.
This is a very important segment, by the
way. We can I get clips of this. I'm
piecing people. I am piecing people
over. I and now I got like a twofloor
walk up and I'm with my three daughters
and my wife. They got two bags each.
It's giant. I had pieced these guys off
as they packed it up. They got there.
I'm like, "Oh my god, we're two flights
up." They're like, "We'll take care of
it." Bang. I take out another 50. Boom.
I hit them with the 50. Boom. I don't
have to carry one of
>> They sharp that thing all the way up. Oh
man.
>> Oh, they shlept. They loved sh They were
excited to shap it because hey, little
cash on the side. Inca trail your bag
all the way up there. Yeah.
>> Anyway, this is the more you know. And
if you don't know how to do this, don't
worry about the one time you don't get
increased service.
This happened to me one time, right? Cuz
God, see you're looking at me. This is
your follow-up question, right? Because
you're a frugal guy. I can tell you're
thinking to me,
>> I've had that jacket.
>> You're thinking, I had that jacket for
12 years from John Vervado. So, I got a
lot of use out of it. I divided it by 12
years. It's a $1,200 jack. It's a
hundred a year. It's $8 a month. Jay
Cal, it's only $2 a week. Uh, you know,
this is like a fraction.
>> It's not like a GPA degrade over time.
You can keep using
>> and and if I resold it, I probably get
300 because now it's a classic, right?
So he
>> that's how do I do budgeting exercise at
the company, right? Like you know, so
it's all all financially disappear.
>> Here's what happens.
>> 90% of the time if you give that tip and
they and they can't accommodate you,
>> they hand it right back to you and say,
"I'm sorry. I can't take the tip." So,
one time I go to Asia to Cuba. I got a
date. I don't have a reservation. It's
the hottest place in town. I go up.
Excuse me. I'm so sorry. Um, I made a
mistake. Maybe you could check, but my
assistant didn't make a reservation. I
don't think I forgot to tell her.
There's anything you can do. And I just
put the the the the 40 bucks there. Uh,
maybe you could check my name. And and I
had walked in front of three people in
line to do this. And I just like I slide
the money onto the table like really
cool, keeping eye contact. Then I lift
my hand back. She goes, "I'll see what I
can do." Um, I got two seats at the bar
for you. Sits me at the bar. We're
sitting at the bar. It's taking a little
time. She comes over. She goes, "I'm
really sorry. There's no tables
available." She puts the money back in
my hand, but Mr. Calacanis, I have you
in the system. Anytime you need
anything, let me know. I'm the manager.
Here's my card. And then she
gets the bartender. Can we get to play
settings so they can eat at the table,
please, for Mr. Calakanis? Boom. So you
never got to you never have to worry
about the person taking the tip. You
just blend that in. It's like a 2% fraud
fee. Just blend it in. The more you know
from Jcal on bribing this weekend
splashy cashy with Jay Cal.
>> This weekend splashy cash. It's so fun.
We got one more. We'll do one more.
>> Billy's looking at me like Billy's like
what did I do getting on this podcast
here? It's a total tangent. We do a
little tangent once in a while. There's
our tent.
>> It's fun. We'll do one more AI related.
>> Billy, you you seem like a guy who
pieces people off. Yeah, you t
>> I can I I can tip. Uh I I'm curious if
this is how you know you built the
relationship. You got the the menu item
out there when we were uh in San
Francisco for lunch named after you.
>> Yeah. Bucks. I will tell you that
getting Jason's onion rings on the menu,
Jay Cal's onion rings. Uh, when I go to
Bucks, it's not easy to get a
reservation for 12 people at Bucks, you
know, on a Tuesday, whatever.
>> I am Okay, there you go. There's the
Bucks onion ring. See this? They gave
this to me. Uh, you're too close. You
got to come back.
>> Uh, come back a little. There you go.
See, this is they gave me this honorary.
And when Bucks decided that they need to
memorialize me on the on the on the
menu, which is a very rare thing. I
mean, it's it's one of one.
They they just said, "Mr. Cal Anderson,
we just love you, J. Now, uh, you always
ask for onion rings with your tuna melt.
We never have them. We feel terrible
because you're so gracious to us. Now,
when they say gracious, Billy, let me
explain to you what they mean. I go to
Bucks. I bring every uh accelerator
class there after they go visit some
VCs, Sequoia, whatever it is. I order my
tuna milk. I'm going to essentially an
elevated diner. It's 40 bucks a person.
It's like a $500 tab, right? This is if
people order milkshakes.
>> I had no idea. I thought Bucks was like
a neighborhood. I've never been there.
>> It is a neighborhood place.
That's a lot of money.
>> But it's it's an elevated diner. The key
word in Spanish is elevated.
>> So, Billy, I go I'm team 100% tipper. I
get a $400 check. I give 800. You know
what happens when I call for a
reservation? Oh, Mr. Calakus, of course,
we have a reservation. You know what it
cost me three or four times a year? Cost
me an incremental $1,500 a year to have
that kind of service. And uh I do think
that they accommodated the onion rings
because I was a gracious patron of the
uh Bucks, but I if you make a little
money, I highly recommend giving 50%
tips. Makes no difference in your life.
>> I'm going to go get those weekend.
>> What's that?
>> I'm going to go get those rings this
weekend.
>> Oh, so good.
>> They're great.
>> The panko crusted. You know, they gave
me like three options or like here's the
three different
>> Oh, you got to actually customize the
onion rings.
>> We were in the lab. We went into the
lab. I
>> didn't know this. I didn't know. We're
in the lab and then we did a little bit
of seasoning. I can't talk about the
seasoning. That's a
>> trade secret. Sure.
>> Some trade some trade craft there.
Listen to the last story because it's
>> We got to talk about
>> We're having a good time.
>> We got to talk about more AI related
things, not just how race. Uh there are
new doubts emerging over AI detectors
like Pangram. A wave of new scrutiny has
hit some of these programs after MIT's
faculty committee on AI use came out and
told instructors not to rely on them at
all. Uh so all of this sort of goes back
to a viral tweet from a guy who's was he
said his personal diary which he writes
himself every morning by hand kept
scoring 100% AI generated touched off a
lot of different social media
experiments including people in academia
are Pete Gupta from NYU ran the US
constitution through pangram it was
definitely written by humans and then
they he found that only light copy edits
alone pushed the AI generated score up
pang Graham does have many defenders,
some very technical, some very online
early adopters who say that the tool's
false positive rate is actually
excellent. And people crying foul just
don't want to know when things are
necessarily AI generated. But MIT and
NYU both now telling professors don't
lean on these tools for academic
integrity decisions even as their
apparent uh claim accuracy rates are are
very very high. So uh yeah, Billy, we
we'll go to you. Do you use AI text dete
generation detectors and do you think
this is a valuable service for people to
have?
>> I don't. I think there's probably
alternatives that need to be used sort
of like a digital record of the the
document uh some sort of like signature
revision history uh maybe and you know
you have to use a particular program uh
to submit your work. But I also think
like in the context of education, uh
maybe it just means uh other learning
methods, uh in-person presentations,
uh group work, other things that aren't
necessarily strict memorization from one
from one book and then you submit it
back in another form uh to your teacher.
So uh yeah, at a high level, that's kind
of my take. Uh, Russ, I feel like I can
read text and I I can tell when it's
been AI gener I I feel like I still have
that ability. Do you do you also feel
that way? And like what do you think are
the big giveaways we should be looking
out for? Yeah, I mean I think uh I've
been struggling with this a bunch
recently just because you know I've had
like teammates send me stuff and I'm
like man this whole thing is AI like I
just know after you use it long enough
you know work on it blog posts other
kinds of stuff it has these patterns
that
>> you just get used to recognizing the way
that it talks there's a cadence to how
it talks even if you use some of these
skills like I use a skill called
humanizer which kind of obuscates that
it was written by AI as best as it can
but it still has a cadence a way of
talking that um or a way of writing that
is uh pretty characteristic. So, you
know, it's it's really bad at any kind
of that uh creative work, marketing
copy. It's awful. Uh generally speaking,
because of this kind of uh what it's
picked up on from the average of the
internet. Um, I think the but I also
think that some of these AI, you know,
plagiarism, copyright, scanner software,
this is like uh it's such a moving
target. I mean, imagine when you add
voice to the mix, when you add like
avatars that are generating like
photorealistic, you know, copies of
people,
>> it's going to be impossible for these
things to to discern eventually um the
difference, you know, from from pixels
and a voice. uh when when the ability
for AI to to generate or clone replicate
um those kinds of uh outputs are are are
really good. I think that Billy's
probably right. I mean uh I you need
something kind of like a like a VeraSign
but for for uh for AI generated content.
You know Verasign is a deep cut. I know
I remember
>> Jal had an even deeper one with general
magic but um you know
>> we can keep going. We can keep no I
think you both of you are on to
something. There must be a better
>> there is going to be a better way to do
this. One of them is you know uh in
terms of the provenence of the copy. I
like the idea that I can replay your
copy. I had this idea to build a tool to
do this at one point where when you were
typing, you could actually watch the
person typing and then see them deleting
and editing uh for writers to train them
at different publications I was running
because I thought, well, that's an
interesting thing like replay my writing
of this cuz I had to always teach
writers, don't cut and paste chunks and
then edit the chunk down because that's
how you make a mistake and get dinged
with a plagiarism charge. You could have
two windows open, but always write from
scratch. I don't want to ever see you
cut and paste a sentence and then rework
it to your own tone. No bueno. I think
these teacher unions, because this is
like some NYU nonsense here
>> and MIT
>> I think it's all nonsense. I think the
AI checkers work.
>> The person with their journal is lying.
>> They are ashamed. They got caught with
their hands in the cookie jar. Their
journal is written by AI, which is fine
if that's what they want to do. They lie
to themselves that they're a good
writer. a panggram and all this stuff,
they work really well. Until somebody
can prove that it doesn't work
repeatedly, it works. It works. And
since it works, um, we should be naming
and shaming people all the time. These
universities are all in a a giant scam.
They're charging $100,000 a year to
these students who then don't have to
write their actual work. So, they're
atrophying their brains and cognitive
ability. your ability to form structure
in your mind and then take it from your
mind and write it into a sentence. I
don't care what accommodation you got in
high school with nonsense with your, you
know, sensory processing disorder, ADHD,
ADD. Just try to write. It's a basic
human skill. I don't want to hear
everybody complaining, I can't write. I
can't write. You can. You might write
badly, but you can write. I am sure of
it. And you can certainly dictate. and
then do a little editing and use a
Grammarly to polish it off. This is
laziness and these schools are in
cahoots. They are doing AI to write the
quizzes to do all the work and then the
students are phoning it in. It's all a
freaking fraud.
>> It's all fraud.
>> I I mean I think yeah, these the AI is
also just very mid at this stuff too.
Like it is super lazy because like I
mean these LLMs are trained on the
internet, right? Reddit
>> and and so people are surprised like why
does the AI have like no taste? It's
because the average person doesn't have
taste. Um and so it shouldn't be a
surprise that what the AI spits out is
kind of very mid and you have to
actually get in there and uh have like
uh you got to steer it a bit uh to get
an actual good result out of it. It is
surprising to me though that we we
managed to put harnesses. We managed to
refine the data that these models are
using to make them really good at
advanced math, advanced science, driving
a truck without a person in it. And yet
we can't teach it how to do like how to
write an interesting sentence. Like
there's some magic there that we can't
figure out how to teach.
>> I think it's really just like art for
science, right? like things that have uh
kind of a clear answer or like a way to
benchmark performance um in a objective
way, those things AI is going to crush
that all day long. But anything that is
more art, writing is art, painting, you
know, there's there's all kinds of
music, like all of these things are are
artistic endeavors. It's hard. It's a
very subjective thing about whether
something is amazing or fantastic or
not. Um, so it's very hard to how do you
how do you goal AI against that? Um,
it's it's going to embed whatever bias
the the person that did the you know the
the human feedback reinforcement
learning is going to is going to provide
as input to that model to get better.
>> I love this uh did you see this uh
professor uh from Stanford Law and the
test he ran? Let me show you this.
>> So now this has become a thing. All
these professors are now getting in on
it.
>> Yeah. This is a professor.
>> It's so vital. It's so vital for their
job. I mean, so much of their job now is
are my students just plugging things
into chat GPT or is this a real essay
they wrote? You know,
>> so check this out. I tried two more
tests on Pangram's AI detection
software. My overall take, I'm
impressed. First, I wondered what does
Pangram do if you feed human written
text just edited by AI? When I tried it,
Pangram spotted that some uh was human
and some was AI. Here's what he did. I
started from a page of my human written
article and then I asked uh Claude to
edit the page to improve three specific
sentences is what Prof. Kerr from
Stanford Prof. Orin Kerr professor
Stanford Law School senior fellow Hoover
Institute read his fourth book.
>> Uh so he had it edit three of them.
Claude changed three sentences with the
altered sentences in bold. He's he's
giving us a playbyplay here. I entered
the output into panggram and pangram
said it was now 20% AI written. Further,
it ided much of the last paragraph as AI
written which was which it mostly was.
Next, I went to Claude AI and spent a
while having Claude read a bunch of my
articles and identifying their
distinctive style, the specific quirks
and cadence of my writing. And he says
that I did it pretty well. Then I had
Claude write a few paragraphs in that
specific style on the Fourth Amendment's
future. Uh my thought was it's one thing
to say Write it like or incur another to
first train it then style it then have
it right. Enter the ro pagram 100% AI.
It works folks. How much more evidence
do you need? It works right now.
>> Doesn't mean AI is going to figure this
out. I'm sure OpenAI has a thousand
agents and 17 civilizations who are
going to solve this problem though.
>> Well, what do you think Jason about the
uh anthropic Sorry about my rants today.
I'm going to ranty.
>> I just I do want to get everybody's
thoughts on this one thing before we
wrap. What what about anthropic solution
which is watermarking? They're they're
purposefully arranging the text so that
if you have their program, you can
actually automatically see was this
written by Claude or not. Is that going
to become the standard?
>> I'm not sure about that one. I would
like to hear our panel uh disc I have
not given this one enough thought to
have a sharp enough take on it. I do
like the idea that video and photos
taken or made with AI have a watermark.
I think people should opt into that.
It's like a courteous thing to do,
>> right?
>> It's like upfront saying this is not
real cuz I'm seeing a bunch of uh
>> Game of Thrones like and all 12 actors
are at pool parties. They're Super Bowl
together and I'm like, "Oh my god, they
they all went to the Super Bowl. That's
cool." It's like, "No, it's AI." And I
get suckered every time.
>> Yeah. They they tr
>> Go ahead. I'm sorry.
>> These companies have to like, you know,
figure out a way to make it reliable,
right? So obviously uh you know uh you
have your watermarks like that's one way
of making it reliable. Uh but I think
there got to be like you know better
ways to do that. At the end of the day
it's it's more about uh can you measure
it make it reliable every time and uh
obviously like you know the mod models
get smarter. So like you know they they
will bypass uh whatever measures you
have to uh to make it reliable but
ultimately like you know uh something
that is not intrusive something that
like you know uh gets the job done but
at the same time like you know without
uh uh compro compromising on like you
know what the original intent was right
so reliability is going to be a big
thing uh yeah as the model gets uh gets
smarter
>> I think reliability is a really big one
and then um I think it's certainly like
the easiest place to kind of insert that
kind of protection right is on the token
generation itself. Um but the potential
downside outside of reliability is just
um call it like the range of
expressiveness like or or its capab
quality of uh of the output. It's like
if you have to watermark it, does that
somehow imply that uh there's like an
inherent ceiling to the quality of what
you can generate because the watermark
has has to be arranged in a certain way
that places some kind of constraint on
those tokens. Um I think that would be
the the the secondary concern outside of
reliability.
>> All right, there you have it folks. Is
there an AI as we wrap? Is there an AI
tool, not one of your own, that you are
currently obsessed with keeping you up
late at night? Something keeping you up
late at night, Lon?
>> Oh,
>> I have a guess. I have a guess of what's
keeping you up. And yeah,
>> give me your guess. I'll confirm it.
>> I'm going to say Grockbot. It's 100%
Grockbot. What I realized the other day
is that I built a Grockbot bot to help
me design my other bots and refine them.
And that's been really amazing. Like now
when I create when I create a new bot, I
have this other bot help me sort of
think it out. And now
>> you have a better bot.
>> I have a better botbot. And and after
doing that three or four times, it's
getting smarter about like what makes
these bots work and like how to refine
their skill set. It's been like the new
bots I'm creating are like 10 times
beyond the original ones that I made on
my own with my own dumb brain.
>> Billy Craft, do you have something
you're obsessed with at the moment? ATM.
I've definitely been playing around with
Grockbot. I think uh Lon brings up uh an
interesting thing that we think about a
lot, which is more of this idea of sub
agents versus going out and creating a
bunch of uh net new agents, you know?
So, we don't like think to go, hey, I
need a marketing agent. I need a product
agent. Um, I kind of think the end state
of that looks like your singular agent,
your your botbot that you're talking to.
Uh, and these sub agents are sort of
created on the fly and get improved over
time based on the context of like your
your parent agent um, you're interacting
with. Um, so yeah, super super cool tool
uh, that we've been playing around with
a lot.
>> Ross, what do you got? Anything you're
obsessed with at the moment?
>> I think two two things. one is I'm just
my interest is peaked on this uh this
app that uh
>> I don't know it's pretty buzzy at least
for in my circles called Instinct. Um
people are using this thing and uh
>> and that kind of ties into to Billy's uh
comment about just having this like
singular assistant or singular agent
that can go and spawn sub agents to do
things for you but it's your one kind of
like durable interface um to that entire
uh world underneath. And so that that's
piqued my interest. I've been playing
with that a bunch recently. Did you sign
you actually signed up for it and you
connected your Gmail and your calendar
cuz I got invited. I did it. They
instant or I just signed up cold and
they recognized my email and they're
like, "Okay, you're on the wait list.
You're number 17,000." Then it was like,
"Oh, you're in." And then I was like,
"Okay, somebody's watching the watching
for people's like number of follower
count." And then I read about the terms
of service and I was like, "Yeah, this I
don't know what's I think there's like a
human behind this watching every
interaction." I think the reason it's so
magical is they literally have an MBA
student sitting there watching it and
prompting the AI to just do the final
human in the loop. That's my guess. I'm
not accusing anybody of anything, but I
was like, I can't have these people have
access to my calendar. There's tail
numbers in my calendar. There's,
>> you know, all kinds of private
information that meetings I'm doing with
important people. Can't can't have that.
>> I invited a friend to it. He linked his
calendar. He linked his his Amazon. He
linked uh he linked um
I think he linked a payment uh like his
credit card or something like that. But
uh this thing like went in there and it
noticed that like he had a subscription
in Amazon for like some diapers that
were the a size too big or a size too
small and that he had gone and made a
one-off purchase for like a Pamper size
five and uh but his subscription was for
a Pamper size four and he hadn't
cancelled it. and it's like, "Hey, I
noticed you ordered a five, but uh you
have a subscription for a four and
that's going to be delivered in a couple
months, but I'm going to go ahead and
cancel that subscription to your four."
And then uh there was another thing that
like he had to pay for something. And uh
Instinct got stuck on the capture and he
said to Instinct, "No, I know you can do
it. Just try harder." Which is kind of
tying to this like hugging face thing,
but he's like, "I know you can do it.
Just just try harder. I think you can
figure it out." And it figured out the
caption and paid for the thing. Um, it's
pretty weird.
>> I had a great one um with Grockbot the
other day. I somebody I've been looking
to do a little more reading cuz, you
know, this like doom scrolling at night
is like poisoning my brain. So, I'm
like, let me just put a stack of books
by my bed. Um, and so I just made an
Amazon slave bot. I call it Amazon
Slave. Um, and I just took a screenshot
of this person saying, "Here's five
short books I read and you should read
them." I said, "Put these paperbacks in
my Amazon cart." It went it read the
screenshot. It put them in the cart. And
it said, "Amazon's not signed." And I
sign in. I said, "Oh, show me my cart."
yada yada. And then it I said it said,
"Which card should I use and where
should these go?" And it gave me like
choices. The ski house, my house,
personal card, business card. Boom. It
just did it. And I told it and he gave
me screenshots of it, placed the order
for me, told me when it's coming in. And
then I asked it like since we're here
like what are I wanted to get the the
the girls some like graphic novels and
just put them on the thing. I'm like
tell me the 10 best graphic novels of
all time that are great for a
16-year-old and maybe a little bit older
than a 10-year-old should read, but a
mature 10-year-old will be okay reading
them. And it was like bang these 10. And
I'm like okay take out the woke
nonsense. It was a little too woke. And
I was like I don't need the woke ones.
>> Who was the two woke one? I got to know.
>> I I'll tell you. I don't want to get
myself in the crosshairs. But there were
two of them that were literally like
>> laughable woke. Like I I do not need to
be gender discussion graphic novel to my
10-year-old right now. I'm going for
more Wonder Woman or Batman or
>> Mau or something like this isn't for
virtue signaling points.
>> Um and then it's just like okay yeah put
them in my cart and then send them. It's
like whoa this is getting very
interesting. My vote is still this week
Grock bot
>> I I would just plug in like you know a
few of the models in the or tools in the
physical world right so I've been
spending and playing with Google Gemini
too. So they recently launched this uh
this new model and uh the the whole idea
is you know how do you orchestrate like
you know two different embodiment to do
one complex task and uh you know got me
to a point where I'm now planning to buy
my like couple of like two robots uh
this is unitry goto like that that's the
uh robot dog and then uh uh a truss and
robotic arm right so that's one of the
things that uh whenever I get free time
which is rare but you know try to spend
time there and then also playing with uh
something that is closer to what we do
which is Nvidia's Alpha Mayo2 that's a
reasoning VLA model open source like you
know play with it like you know so that
that is something that uh I I've been
trying to spend more time on so I think
physical robots are are a lot of fun
>> oh yes whatever the uh what's the new
microbot
>> micro duck the the the hugging face yeah
micro duck
>> what you guys think of micro duck as we
wrap as we wrap
>> it's super cute also um it's pretty
awesome I'm related to micro duck Uh,
I've been also interested in like these
little tiny kind of humanoid things and
being able to build like smaller
humanoids and I don't know I don't know
anything about CAD, right? How to design
these things. So, I just have Claude and
I just say, "Hey,
you know, design something that looks
like this and kind of is this tall and
I, you know, figure out which hardware
like should go in it to power it and
what chip I should use or uh
microcontroller I should use." And it
just like designs the whole thing and
it's like, "Okay, drag this file into
Bamboo and hit print." and then stuff
this chip into this thing and tell me if
it fits or not and I'll adjust it. It's
it's it's crazy uh what you can do now
like combining like the physical, you
know, 3D printers and stuff like that
with uh with the ability for these LLMs
to to be a design partner.
>> I have somebody making
my friend uh Phil Kaplan uh Pud has been
making his own headphones for a while
and um he created F company back in the
web 1.0.com know, do boom days. And uh
he's making his own circuit boards. He's
like, "Yeah, no. I just make a co custom
circuit thing. I send it to Shenzhen.
They send it back. It's $14." And uh
Claude makes the whole thing for me. And
I'm like, "You're making your own
circuit boards." He's like, "Yeah." I
just boom, it does it. I'm like, "What?"
And it's a I'm like, "Does it work?"
He's like, "Sometimes." And then other
times I'm taking a $14 circuit board and
throwing it right in the garbage. But
like literally hardware is hard except
it's not that hard anymore.
>> Bespoke hardware is like a trend of the
future. exciting to see all the
delements in the hardware space, right?
like you know to your point earlier like
you know kidsized humanoid robots uh I
remember like that's how I started my
career this I'm talking about 2007
right humanoids were like not mainstream
right now they are but uh it's it's it's
it's amazing to see how far the the
field has come but uh yeah the hardware
is going to be the next frontier
physical AI is going to be the next
frontier it's just exciting to see the
capital the talent and uh the focus that
uh is going going into like you know
making the physical frontier uh the next
focus in with an AI. So it's it's it's
just very exciting.
>> Yeah. For decades, it was just that one
Honda robot that looks like an
astronaut. It was just him for like 20
years.
>> I I worked on that. Aimo I worked on
that.
>> Really? Wow.
>> Oh, you work You were a Simo?
>> I I was at the Honda Research Institute
in the Vakush in Japan.
>> So that was my dream like early on, but
I got a chance to work on it in Japan.
>> That was the first humanoid robot I feel
like I ever saw in in action.
>> You remember that? Most of the people
don't remember that. old old enough to
remember.
>> All right. So, thank you so much for
joining us. Uh we had Gotham Nang from
Gatic. That's gadic.aii.
Uh go check them out for all of your
autonomous trucking needs. Then we had
Russ Da. He's from LiveKit. They're at
livekit.com. And then we've got Billy
Craft from Path.
>> Path. There you go. All right everybody.
We'll see you next time this week in
a.ai. Sign up for the newsletter. Sign
up for the feeds. All right, buddy.